<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on ASPBGJ</title>
    <link>https://asepbagja.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on ASPBGJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>2019 © Asep Bagja Priandana</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 19:03:43 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://asepbagja.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apa Itu Estonia e-Residency?</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/apa-itu-estonia-e-residency/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 19:03:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/apa-itu-estonia-e-residency/</guid>
      <description>Saya sering sekali mendapat pertanyaan dari teman atau kenalan setiap kali mereka melihat website Tanibox, &amp;ldquo;Loh, Tanibox itu alamatnya di Estonia? Kok, bisa? Kenapa?&amp;rdquo; Untuk menjawab pertanyaan ini, saya harus memulai dengan menjelaskan program Estonia e-Residency. Sedangkan untuk menjawab pertanyaan, &amp;ldquo;kenapa kok Estonia?&amp;rdquo;, kamu bisa memulai kisah awalnya di tulisan saya pada tahun 2017 di sini.
Menjadi panelist di Running Remote Conference 2019 bersama tim dari pemerintah Estonia untuk program e-Residency</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights to Sell Agritech Product</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/insights-agritech-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 10:31:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/insights-agritech-product/</guid>
      <description>My company Tanibox is developing agriculture software for two years. We focus on Tania, our open source farm management software. We love growing plants, but we&amp;ndash;all co-founders of Tanibox&amp;ndash;never touch agriculture as an industry before Tanibox exist. So, we jumped to agriculture technology industry by trial and error. Here are some interesting insights from a couple of years building an open source software for agriculture to share with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Back to My Personal Web</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/going-back-to-my-personal-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 11:30:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/going-back-to-my-personal-web/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last post on this website. Three years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s time to dust off and start writing again. I want to challenge my self, &amp;ldquo;how if I make this blog like a social media?&amp;rdquo; I will prioritise to post anything here instead of posting in social media whether it&amp;rsquo;s a short or long content.
This blog post is the first attempt. Wish me luck with the idea!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Asep Bagja Priandana from Indonesia. You can call me Asep. I grew up in several cities in Indonesia. My family was a nomadic because my father worked as a government auditor. I studied accounting in Universitas Islam Indonesia. Despite of my formal education background, I started my professional career as a web developer in 2009 because technology is my passion.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m a paralel entrepreneur. I manage and co-found my companies: Tanibox and Chloè &amp;amp; Matt, together with my wife, Retno Ika Safitri.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terima Kasih Froyo. Asep Is Out!</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/terima-kasih-froyo-asep-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 19:02:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/terima-kasih-froyo-asep-is-out/</guid>
      <description>A mic dropped is taken from Flickr.
Awal tahun 2017, seperti tahun-tahun sebelumnya saya membuat sebuah resolusi yang saya tuliskan di blog. Tidak seperti resolusi tahun-tahun sebelumnya yang saya tuliskan cukup panjang, tahun ini artikel tentang resolusi saya sangat singkat. Saya mau melakukan Mars-shot (istilah karangan saya sendiri,) karena moonshot menurut saya masih terlalu kecil.
Bulan Februari 2017, saya menyatakan niat untuk exit dari bisnis Froyo — perusahaan yang saya bangun bersama rekan saya Andika Alivano sejak 2012 (awalnya masih bernama Amazing Milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Functional Programming in JavaScript (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/introduction-to-functional-programming-in-javascript-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/introduction-to-functional-programming-in-javascript-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In part 1, we had learned about two important concepts in functional programming paradigm: immutable data and pure function. Now, we will learn another important concept in functional programming, that is higher order function.
According to Wikipedia, higher-order function is a function that does at least one of the following:
 takes one or more functions as arguments returns a function as its results.  JavaScript has the first-class function. It means the functions in JavaScript treats as a value, that we can assign it to the variable, pass it around, and return from another function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Functional Programming in JavaScript (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/introduction-to-functional-programming-in-javascript-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/introduction-to-functional-programming-in-javascript-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Imperative programming is a programming paradigm that uses a sequence of statements to reach a certain goal. It focuses on how to perform actions to achieve the expected result. Otherwise, functional programming paradigm concentrates on computing results rather than performing actions. In another word, the imperative one is an annoying micromanager in your office, and the functional one is a macromanager who just describe what&amp;rsquo;s the job to be done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Free SSL to Existing WordPress Site with Docker and Let&#39;s Encrypt</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/add-free-ssl-to-existing-wordpress-site-with-docker-and-lets-encrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/add-free-ssl-to-existing-wordpress-site-with-docker-and-lets-encrypt/</guid>
      <description>Google announced that they use HTTPS as a ranking signal on 2014, and it becomes more standard in their search result. Therefore, I decide to use HTTPS also for this blog; and it looks pretty too for having a green lock icon on the browser. I&amp;rsquo;m a Docker devotee, so I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to do it by using Docker.
1. Install Docker on the server
I&amp;rsquo;m using Ubuntu 16.04 on my Digital Ocean droplet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did I Start to Invest in The Stock Market?</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/why-did-i-start-to-invest-in-the-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/why-did-i-start-to-invest-in-the-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Most of you perhaps ever heard or read about The Cashflow Quadrant by Robert Kiyosaki. I bought his book when I was a high school student. The book explained about quadrant of economic roles: employee, self-employed, business owner, and investor. The employee is people who have a job, I was. The self-employed is individuals who own a job, I was. The business owner is individuals who have a system that produces cash flow for themselves and other work for them; this is me now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016 Personal Challenges</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/2016-personal-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/2016-personal-challenges/</guid>
      <description>Happy new year 2016.
Annually I challenged myself with some new skills and some targets. Few years ago, I challenged myself to learn Mandarin, because it is the most spoken language in Asia. Therefore, I took a Mandarin short course and also self-learning it via Youtube.
I had also challenged myself to learn functional programming paradigm and tried to master one of the programming languages that used that paradigm. My choice was Clojure because it is using Lisp dialect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple, Cheap, and Scalable IoT Data Logging With Clojure</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/simple-and-cheap-iot-data-logging-with-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/simple-and-cheap-iot-data-logging-with-clojure/</guid>
      <description>I have a small green house in my home front yard, and I deployed some sensors like temperature, humidity, electrical conductivity (EC), and pH sensor there.
After the development of the sensors completed, it was the time for me to develop the web service for logging the data. I considered to use NoSQL database for persistent data storage. Otherwise I dismissed that idea for the sake of cost efficiency.
To use NoSQL database, I should open one or two servers in cloud provider for running it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geekcamp Jakarta 2015. Programmable Music</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/geekcamp-jakarta-2015-programmable-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/geekcamp-jakarta-2015-programmable-music/</guid>
      <description>Geekcamp Jakarta 2015 is a technology and business conference organized by KMKLabs. This is my presentation about computer generated music using Clojure and Overtone. The talk is using Bahasa Indonesia, but here I try to give the English transcript.
 Transcript
[00:20] I want to talk about music. Who loves music here? I&amp;rsquo;m sure many of you loves music.
[00:27] Are there many programmers here? Because it will relates with code also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Family’s Journey to Grow Our Own Food</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/my-familys-journey-to-grow-our-own-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/my-familys-journey-to-grow-our-own-food/</guid>
      <description>My wife&amp;rsquo;s dream after we married was having a garden at home. But at that moment, we were living in an apartment with a very small balcony. It&amp;rsquo;s theoritically impossible to plant anything. So, we discovered a way to plant vegetable at small space and we found it. Hydroponic was the answer. We can plant without soil but only water.
The Age of Farming in The Apartment
At the first time, we were growing spinach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Not Refuse The Corporate Culture</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/do-not-refuse-the-corporate-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/do-not-refuse-the-corporate-culture/</guid>
      <description>A letter from my dad about how to make my company bigger.
My dad was a government auditor for 35 years plus. He never expected me to be an entrepreneur. At the first, he did not support me, but now he is the one who regularly give me advices about running a company.
A few days ago, he sent me an email (in Bahasa Indonesia) that I thought it was a very good advice and I would like to share it to another startup founder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 Years Old. Do Something Matters Now.</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/28-years-old-do-something-matters-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/28-years-old-do-something-matters-now/</guid>
      <description>Today, September 21, 2015, I&amp;rsquo;m officially 28 years old.
Many people say 28 is the starting age to enter adulthood. In astrology, they call it Saturn Return. It is a period for Saturn completing its full orbit around the Sun, and Saturn is returning to the position when the people were born.
Whatever people talk about the age of 28, I believe it is the age for starting something matters and meaningful in my life and my career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban Farming with Clojure</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/urban-farming-with-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/urban-farming-with-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m developing an indoor farming system to grow vegetables (at the moment is Lettuce) and herbs in my house. You can check the project&amp;rsquo;s progress on my Hackaday&amp;rsquo;s page. The system should controls the lighting on and off at the correct time, logs the temperature and humidity and triggers the fan based on it, and sends the farm log to the server, so, I can predict the harvest time and the farm optimal condition in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R.I.P All of My Fish. Postmortem of A Hardware Automation Project</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/r-i-p-all-of-my-fish-postmortem-of-a-hardware-automation-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/r-i-p-all-of-my-fish-postmortem-of-a-hardware-automation-project/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest problem of having pet is filling its needs while the owner leaving the home.
I had an aquarium which was filled with 7 fish, and the fish should be fed at least once a day or better twice a day in small portion. A week ago, I and my wife must left our home for celebrating Eid together at my parent&amp;rsquo;s home in another town, thus it led me for creating an automation system to feed my fish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Clojure Project</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/full-stack-clojure-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/full-stack-clojure-project/</guid>
      <description>Why I&amp;rsquo;m deeply in love with Clojure? That&amp;rsquo;s because I can do full stack development only in one language. I can write HTML with the same Clojure data structure, then styling it by writing CSS in exactly the same data structure. When I need to do user interface development, I can use ClojureScript then compile it into JavaScript. Actually writing ClojureScript is more pleasant than writing vanilla JavaScript. How about the backend development?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating React Bootstrap and Reagent</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/integrating-react-bootstrap-and-reagent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/integrating-react-bootstrap-and-reagent/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, I am experimenting to use React Bootstrap with ClojureScript. For whom that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know it yet, React Bootstrap is a Bootstrap 3 component built with ReactJS. I&amp;rsquo;m using Reagent library for interacting with React from ClojureScript, instead of Om.
Integrating React Bootstrap and Reagent was confusing me at the first. It was non-trivial effort. I searched Google and got no relevant solutions for hours. So, this working solution is based on my trial and error experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Learning Curve In IoT World As A Web and iOS Developer</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/my-learning-curve-in-iot-world-as-a-web-and-ios-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/my-learning-curve-in-iot-world-as-a-web-and-ios-developer/</guid>
      <description>As a web developer and iOS developer, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know much about hardware or bare metal programming. I only learned about resistor, capasitor, transistor, etc when I was still in junior high school, thus my electronic knowledge is very limited.
Arduino Uno R3. My First Board.
I was interested for learning electronic again as a hobby around 2-3 years ago, when I read that Arduino is easy for learning micro controller programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Learning to Code Necessary for Everyone?</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/is-learning-to-code-necessary-for-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/is-learning-to-code-necessary-for-everyone/</guid>
      <description>Although coding is not a basic communication skill for human, I prefer to encourage people for learning it, especially for someone who wants to expresses and develops his/her idea in technology industry but doesn&amp;rsquo;t come from computer science background. There are couple of reasons according to that opinion.
In the first place, if people know basic coding skill, he/she can develop his/her very beginning concept of software by his/her own hand, then his/her can show it to the more appropriate software engineer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me and Programming Languages</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/me-and-programming-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/me-and-programming-languages/</guid>
      <description>This is the story of my life about my relationship with some programming languages from the first time I learnt computer programming until now. It was like finding a life partner.
Pascal
I met her around 2003 from my high school accounting teacher. She was my very first date in programming world. I tried to digest how to do programming and what I can do with programming. My relationship with Pascal was very short.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>