<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>business on ASPBGJ</title>
    <link>https://asepbagja.com/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in business on ASPBGJ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 10:31:50 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://asepbagja.com/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights to Sell Agritech Product</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/insights-agritech-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 10:31:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/insights-agritech-product/</guid>
      <description>My company Tanibox is developing agriculture software for two years. We focus on Tania, our open source farm management software. We love growing plants, but we&amp;ndash;all co-founders of Tanibox&amp;ndash;never touch agriculture as an industry before Tanibox exist. So, we jumped to agriculture technology industry by trial and error. Here are some interesting insights from a couple of years building an open source software for agriculture to share with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Did I Start to Invest in The Stock Market?</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/why-did-i-start-to-invest-in-the-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/why-did-i-start-to-invest-in-the-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Most of you perhaps ever heard or read about The Cashflow Quadrant by Robert Kiyosaki. I bought his book when I was a high school student. The book explained about quadrant of economic roles: employee, self-employed, business owner, and investor. The employee is people who have a job, I was. The self-employed is individuals who own a job, I was. The business owner is individuals who have a system that produces cash flow for themselves and other work for them; this is me now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Not Refuse The Corporate Culture</title>
      <link>https://asepbagja.com/posts/do-not-refuse-the-corporate-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://asepbagja.com/posts/do-not-refuse-the-corporate-culture/</guid>
      <description>A letter from my dad about how to make my company bigger.
My dad was a government auditor for 35 years plus. He never expected me to be an entrepreneur. At the first, he did not support me, but now he is the one who regularly give me advices about running a company.
A few days ago, he sent me an email (in Bahasa Indonesia) that I thought it was a very good advice and I would like to share it to another startup founder.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>